He is afraid. He is totally alone. He is 3,000,000 light years from home.
E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial is a science fiction, adventure,
family film directed by Steven Spielberg.
An alien is left behind on Earth and saved by the 10-year-old
Elliott who decides to keep him hidden in his home.
While a task force hunts for the extra-terrestrial, Elliott, his brother, and his little sister Gertie
form an emotional bond with their new friend, and try to help him find his way home.
Elliott, played by Henry Thomas.
Gertie, played by Drew Barrymore.
Michael, played by Robert MacNaughton.
Keys, played by Peter Coyote.
Mary, played by Dee Wallace.
Pretty Girl, played by Erika Eleniak.
the Extra-Terrestrial (or simply E.T.) is a 1982 American science fiction film
produced and directed by Steven Spielberg and written by Melissa Mathison.
It tells the story of Elliott, a boy who befriends an
extraterrestrial that he names E.T.
who has been stranded on Earth.
Along with his friends and family, Elliott must find a way to help E.T.
find his way home.
The film stars Dee Wallace, Henry Thomas, Peter Coyote,
Robert MacNaughton, and Drew Barrymore.
The film's concept was based on an imaginary friend that
Spielberg created after his parents' divorce.
In 1980, Spielberg met Mathison and developed a new story
from the unrealized project Night Skies.
In less than two months, Mathison wrote the first
draft of the script, titled E.T.
and Me, which went through two rewrites.
The project was rejected by Columbia Pictures, who
doubted its commercial potential.
Universal Pictures eventually purchased the script for $1 million.
Filming took place from September to December 1981 on a budget of $10.5 million.
Unlike most films, E.T.
was shot in rough chronological order to facilitate convincing
emotional performances from the young cast.
The animatronics for the film were designed by Carlo Rambaldi.
premiered as the closing film of the Cannes Film Festival on May 26,
1982, and was released in the United States on June 11.
The film was a smash hit at the box office, surpassing Star Wars (1977) to become the highest-grossing film of all
time, a record it held for eleven years until Spielberg's own Jurassic Park surpassed it in 1993.
received universal acclaim from critics, and is regarded as one of
the greatest and most influential films ever made.
It received nine nominations at the 55th Academy Awards, winning Best Original Score, Best Visual Effects, Best
Sound, and Best Sound Editing in addition to being nominated for Best Picture and Best Director.
It also won five Saturn Awards and two Golden Globe Awards.
The film was re-released in 1985 and again in 2002 to celebrate its 20th
anniversary, with altered shots, visual effects, and additional scenes.
It was also re-released in IMAX on August 12, 2022,
to celebrate its 40th anniversary.
In 1994, the film was added to the United States National Film Registry of the Library of
Congress, who deemed it "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant."
The film explores themes of farewell, space
marine, operation, flying saucer, nasa.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.